# **ARUNN SHANMUGAM**

# Technical Design Lead

arunnshanmugam@gmail.com +44 7880807900

Crawley, UK <a href="mailto:linkedin.com/in/arunnshanmugam">linkedin.com/in/arunnshanmugam</a>

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Technical Design Lead**

#### Cognizant

July 2021 – Present

Crawley, UK

- Had designed and developed .Net Core 6 C# based web app and web API and have setup web applications in Azure Kubernetes with dynaflo devops.
- Had designed and developed C# .Net core 6.0 based thick client console apps connecting to Kafka. based on the pub-sub architecture.
- Have assisted Architecture on all aspects of business application planning and development.
- Coordinated with technical managers to ensure completion of client sign-offs.
- Used codes and flowcharts to develop technical documentation and reports.
- Supported work flow management infrastructure components in alignment with business objectives.
- Reconciled interface of external and internal application systems.
- Azure Developer Associate (AZ-204) Certified.
- Supported in migrating applications to cloud.
- Approached each problem with fresh mind and analytical strategies to quickly resolve concerns

### **Team Lead**

#### **Cognizant**

July 2018 – June 2021 Chennai, India

- Proficient with C# programming language, .Net Core and have hands on experience on various .Net project including thick and thin client Application (.net core and framework), REST APIs and WCF Web services based in C#, UNIX Shell
- Developed python applications for document management,
  Designed and developed .Net application using Web API,
  WCF, MVC, .Net Core and Frame work thick client
  executables. Have hands-on experience developing utilities in
  Unix Shell, windows power shell scripts. Managed systems
  integrating through secure data transfer (SFTP).
- Proficient in data base Queries with DB2 and SQL. Worked with dev-ops team to setup CI/CD for .Net apps. Helped to resolve issues during the implementation and also during the entire setup of pipeline process to meet customer standards.

### **SUMMARY**

Energetic and Skilled, Lead Developer with 11+ year background in designing and building functional programs. Able to write clear and concise technical specifications. Excellent troubleshooting talents with the ability to solve complex issues in an effective and professional manner.

### **SKILLS**

- C#, .Net Core 6, Web API, Kafka MQ
- Azure Kubernetes, dynaflo, devops
- IBM DB2, Microsoft SQL Server
- IBM FileNet CE and PE, document and case/workflow management
- VSTO Office Add-Ins, SSRS Reporting
- UNIX Shell and Python
- GitHub (CI/CD) and Agile workflow process
- Azure functions & Azure Apps

## **EDUCATION**

**Bachelors in Electronics and Communication Engineering** 

2007 - 2011

Completed Bachelor's degree in Bannari Amman Institute of Technology, Tamil Nadu, India with

CGPA: 8.04

- Collaborated with cross-functional development team members to analyze potential system solutions based on evolving client requirements.
- Trained and mentored junior developers and working to improve overall team performance. Have managed a team of 15 people and could able to multi task managing application delivery and mentor the team.
- Worked with Customer IT Team to setup a Production platform for the application that our team developed as an Onshore Lead developer. Performed testing on application to uncover bugs and troubleshoot Memory and Performance issues before application launches.

### **CERTIFICATION**

AZ-204 Azure Developer Associate

OCT 2021

Completed Microsoft certification on Azure developer associate (AZ-204)

#### **Associate Senior Developer**

#### **Cognizant**

Apr 2014 – Jun 2018 Chennai, India

- Worked for a client in Insurance Domain.
- Developed Outlook VSTO Add-In applications in C#. And developed few applications using Python /UNIX Shell.
- Analyzed the cold fusion code and learned Business and technical requirement from the application. Rewroite the application in C# .Net framework ASP.NET using Entity Framework with SQL as backend.
- Have involved in support and development of a VB6 application (document management system).
- Managed a team of 2 to 8 persons, have involved in mentoring new joiners to team. Knowledge transfer and managing tasks and team engagement activities.
- Prepared technical requirements document and worked on application and data model design of the re-write application and the outlook Add-In.
- Worked extensively in database queries and worked on the performance tuning of the scripts.

#### **Associate Developer**

#### **Cognizant**

Aug 2011 – Mar 2014 Chennai, India

- Worked for a client in Banking Domain.
- Worked in C# .net thick client and thin client applications and proficient in SQL server queries.
- Involved in testing of the application and fixed issues effectively. Developed ASP.NET web form application with SQL as backend.
- Involved in gathering business and technical requirements from the client for development of SSRS reports.
- Prepared technical requirements document by writing queries in SQL and on analysis of business requirements.
- Created internal Applications portal for team engagement and to maintain the SCM process. Kept track on uploading and updating the business and technical documents related to project.

Date: Arunn Shanmugam

Place: Crawley, UK